Jinsong Liu

Digital Product Designer / Portfolio: sylvesterlau.com

Jinsong Liu (Sylvester Lau) is a digital product designer with four years of experience in finance, retail, and e-learning. He recently graduated from MA User Experience Design at the University of the Arts London. Holding a continued interest in humantechnology relationships, he aspired to become a full-stack designer. His work appreciates collaboration, unexpected processes and measurable results.

sylvester.lau@outlook.com

+86 156 2231 9121

View LinkedIn profile

EDUCATION

2020.10 — 2021.12

2013.9 — 2017.7

University of the Arts London

Guangdong University of Technology

User Experience Design, Master of Arts

Industrial Design, Bachelor of Engineering

LANGUAGE

English

IELTS Academic 7.5 / CEFR C1

Chinese / Cantonese

Native Speaker

WORK EXPERIENCE

2021.10 – 2021.12 Product Designer (Part-time) W12 Studios

London, UK

Participated in new features design for Verizon TV and Dashboard

2021.3 — 2021.7 **UX Designer** Master's Degree Projects

London, UK

Worked with external partners, including: Explored a Human-Robot Interaction research method with body-storming with Moley Robotics; and VR exhibition "Silk Road: Asia" with the V&A Museum

2020.2 – 2020.8 UI/UX Designer (Part-time) Runwise Co.

Guangzhou, China

Design for company website on Wordpress and e-learning content

2018.5 — 2019.8 Retail Project Design Lead Runwise Co.

Guangzhou, China

I led the design team of a digitalisation project for Kungfu Restaurant Co, China's top Chinese fast-food brand. Collaborated with project managers, engineers and the marketing team, we delivered an omnichannel online order system (App, Kiosk, Dashboard) with a design system. The project raised online customer retention to 55% and helped the company ready for the unexpected COVID-19 pandemic.

2017.7 — 2018.5 **Junior Product Designer Runwise Co.**

Guangzhou, China

I crafted interfaces, illustrations and infographics for Refuel, an elearning app on lean-product, agile management and other skills.

2016.6 — 2016.12 Interaction Design Intern ETU Design

Guangzhou, China

I collaborated with senior designers and user researchers to design user flow, wireframes interfaces. Clients included China Mobile HK, China Merchants Bank.

AWARDS

Cited Project in Italian Festival of Complexity 2021

Individual

WeChat Smart Retail Award 2018

Team

SKILLS

Interview

Co-design Workshop Rapid Prototyping Design System Data-driven Design

Agile thinking
Usability Testing
Life Learner

TOOLS

Figma

Sketch

HTML/CSS/JavaScript Physical Prototyping

Notion

Always trying new tools

刘劲松

数字产品设计师 / 作品集: https://sylvesterlau.com

我是一名有4年经验的数字产品设计师,曾参与零售、在线教育、金融等领域的数字化转型项目,目前毕业于伦敦艺术大学的用户体验设计硕士专业。我对科技行业和工具类应用有长期热情,在工作中注重团队合作,创意过程和可量化指标,正朝着全栈设计师努力。

sylvester.lau@outlook.com

+86 156 2231 9121

查看领英档案

教育背景

2020.10 — 2021.12

2013.9 — 2017.7

伦敦艺术大学

广东工业大学

用户体验设计,文学硕士

工业设计,工程学士

语言能力

英语

IELTS Academic 7.5 / CEFR C1

中文/粤语

母语水平

工作经历

2021.10 - 2021.12

产品设计师(兼职) W12 Studios

英国,伦敦

负责 Verizon TV 智能电视平台及数据后台的新功能设计和优化

奖项

Italian Festival of Complexity 2021 研讨会引用项目

微信 2018 年度智慧零售奖

个人奖项

团队奖项

2021.3 — 2021.7 用户体验设计师 硕士合作项目

英国,伦敦

参与外部合作项目,包括:与 Moley Robotics 运用 body-storming 探索厨房 机器人互动的设计研究方法;与 V&A 博物馆合作,探索疫情下的展馆体验,设计 Silk Road: Asia VR 展览

2020.2 - 2020.8

2018.5 — 2019.8

UI/UX 设计师(兼职) Runwise 咨询

零售项目主设计师 Runwise 咨询

中国,广州

中国,广州

负责公司官网设计,Wordpress 建站及在线课程资料设计

专业技能

用户访谈

共创工作坊

快速原型

设计系统

数据驱动设计

敏捷思维

可用性测试

终身学习者

2017.7 — 2018.5 **初级产品设计师 Runwise** 咨询

中国,广州

负责「即能」在线教育小程序设计,与产品经理从零到一搭建产品,工作包含访谈、竞品分析、界面设计、信息图、插画及前端开发对接

我在真功夫餐饮集团数字化咨询项目中担任主设计师,驱动小型敏捷设计团

队,与产品经理、开发和市场营销团队深度合作,为客户交付包括微信小程

逐渐建立并执行从用户调研、敏捷原型、设计系统到测试反馈的设计流程。该项目让顾客留存率提升55%,为随后到来的疫情打下数字化服务基础

序、Andriod 平板点餐系统和数据营销后台的全渠道数字化方案。项目期间我

工具

Figma

Sketch

HTML/CSS/JavaScript Physical Prototyping

Notion

Always trying new tools

2016.6 — 2016.12 **交互设计实习 ETU Design**

协助高级设计师和用户研究员,参与调研、用户流程规划、交互和视觉设计 提案。客户包括招商银行、中国移动(香港)等

中国,广州